Whether at school, college or work, most of us take some sort of lunch break.
无论是在学校、大学还是工作中，我们大多数人都会有某种形式的午休时间。
It‘s a good time to have a rest, catch up with friends and eat some food - but here lies the dilemma - what to eat?
这是一个休息、和朋友聊聊天以及吃点东西的好时机——但这里存在一个两难境地——吃什么呢？
There are a feast of options but because of limited time or money, many of us stick to what we know - usually the humble sandwich.
选择可谓丰富多样，但由于有限的时间或金钱，我们很多人还是继续选择我们熟悉的食物——通常就是简单的三明治。
Some of us make our own sandwiches in the morning before heading out, whilst those in a rush tend to grab-and-go at a snack bar or a cafe or buy a meal deal at a supermarket.
我们中的一些人会在早上出门前自己制作三明治，而那些匆忙的人则倾向于在小吃店或咖啡馆买了就走，或者在超市购买套餐。
A packet of crisps may be an additional staple to our predictable lunch.
一包薯片可能是我们可以预见的午餐中额外的主食。
What we eat is usually the same everyday.
我们每天吃的东西通常都是一样的。
Sheila Dillon from the BBC Food Programme says more than a third of office workers have eaten the same midday meal for the last nine months.
英国广播公司美食节目的希拉·狄龙说，在过去的九个月里，超过三分之一的上班族每天吃的午餐都是一样的。
In the UK, bread has become the mainstay of our lunchtime snack, sometimes eaten at your desk - a style known as ’al-desko‘.
在英国，面包已经成为我们午间快餐的主要部分，有时人们会在办公桌前吃——这种方式被称为“在办公桌旁用餐”。
Bread is cheap and fills you up and with average lunch hours now reduced to 25 minutes, 24 seconds, it‘s quick and convenient to eat.
面包价格便宜，能让你吃饱，而且现在平均午餐时间缩短到了25分钟24秒，吃起来又快又方便。
But it's also boring!
但它也很无趣！
Some people have broken the mould by bringing in leftovers from their previous night‘s dinner, which they then heat up in a microwave but even that isn't very exciting.
一些人打破了这种模式，把前一晚晚餐的剩菜带来，然后用微波炉加热，但即便如此也不是很令人兴奋。
We are creatures of habit but philosopher Julian Baggini says “we‘re never going to break out of our midday malaise unless we think outside the box.”
我们是习惯的产物，但哲学家朱利安·巴吉尼说：“除非我们跳出常规思维，否则我们永远无法摆脱中午的这种不适状态。”
There are alternatives that will fill you up.
还有其他能让你吃饱的选择。
With just a microwave and a kettle, there are a number of hot satisfying meals than can be made such as soups and jacket potatoes served with a dollop of baked beans or cheese.
只要有一个微波炉和一个水壶，就可以做出许多令人满足的热食，比如汤和烤土豆，再配上一大块焗豆或奶酪。
And then there are the ubiquitous instant noodles in a pot - although you may question how nutritious they are.
然后还有无处不在的即食泡面——尽管你可能会质疑它们的营养价值。
If you‘ve got time for more exotic munchies, then look out for trendy ’Ottolenghi‘ style food such as fava bean salad wrap.
如果你有时间享用更异国风味的小吃，那就留意一下时尚的“奥托伦吉”风格的食物，比如蚕豆沙拉卷。
There is also the healthy Japanese style ’bento box‘ or lunchbox that normally contains a mix of carbohydrate, protein and vegetable.
还有健康的日式“便当盒”，通常里面包含碳水化合物、蛋白质和蔬菜的混合搭配。
And of course another healthy Japanese treat is sushi.
当然，另一种健康的日式美食就是寿司。
But if I’ve got time for a proper lunch, I head to my local greasy spoon and tuck into a fry-up.
但如果我有时间吃一顿像样的午餐，我会去当地的廉价小餐馆，尽情享用一顿油炸食物。
Not very healthy but delicious and it sets me up for an afternoon of hard work.
虽然不是很健康，但很美味，而且能让我为一下午的辛勤工作做好准备。
Then it‘s time for the next dilemma - what to have for dinner?!
然后就到了下一个两难境地——晚餐吃什么呢？！
What do you usually eat for lunch?
你通常午餐吃什么呢？